<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random Advice on Aravind Reddy</title>
    <link>http://aravindreddy.org/tags/random-advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random Advice on Aravind Reddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Aravind Reddy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:36:51 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/random-advice/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GRE Craxx Algo</title>
      <link>http://aravindreddy.org/post/gre-craxx-algo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:36:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aravindreddy.org/post/gre-craxx-algo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I was probably the first person in my batch of ~830 students at IIT Kanpur to have taken the GRE, I keep receiving a barrage of questions from my both my batchmates and juniors regarding how to &amp;lsquo;crack&amp;rsquo; the GRE. So, here goes the Algo which I employed to improve my score from 324 to 332 within ~10 days of preparation while studying seriously(sorta) for around 3-4 hours a day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ets.org/gre/revised_general/prepare/powerprep/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Practice Test&lt;/a&gt; from the GRE website and take the exam using a timer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide your target score. As far as I know, a bad GRE score hurts your chances of selection but a great score doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve your chances. As a basic guideline, any score below 320 will hurt your chances of getting into a top 100 university and any score above 330 should be fine (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ets.org/s/gre/pdf/gre_guide_table1a.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; the percentile chart).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The verbal section is the one which requires the most preparation (for most Asian students). So, I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on that first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no set syllabus for the verbal section. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to improve your vocab in any way possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting now, make a habit of looking up the meaning of every unknown word you encounter. This will help you immensely because you&amp;rsquo;ll learn holistically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give a list of books which I used to prepare. But as I stated earlier, there&amp;rsquo;s no set syllabus and there&amp;rsquo;s a myriad of books out there which will increase your score. Pick a couple of them and make sure you complete them/revise them regularly before moving onto more books:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.in/dp/9332537860/ref=cm_sw_r_cp_dp_T1_qarvzb42BC29H&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manhattan review: The GRE Complete Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/dp/B008BA9CUA/ref=cm_sw_r_cp_dp_T1_6brvzb75DPJ4B&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GRE Vocab Capacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GRE Vocab Flash cards app from Magoosh(iOS/Android) - Definitely do the basic ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Quant section, you can choose to prepare from the Manhattan review(if you think it&amp;rsquo;ll improve your score). I got a perfect score on the first practice test. So, I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to prepare for the Quant section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The AWA section is a little tricky. I didn&amp;rsquo;t prepare much but I felt that I wrote one good essay and one decent essay and so I expected a 4.&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;(they give you the average of both the sections, 6 points for each essay) but I only got a score of 4. Since this is subjective, it can get really arbit. I would suggest reading the guidelines in the &amp;ldquo;Official Guide to the GRE Verbal Reasoning Practice Questions Volume 1&amp;rdquo; and then picking topics from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ets.org/gre/revised_general/prepare/analytical_writing/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GRE website&lt;/a&gt; and practicing with a timer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the day before your GRE date, complete the second practice test. This should give you a good estimate of your score.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
